pgeverydaysolutions.com 2019-06-24

# P&G Global Consumer Privacy Policy

We work hard to build and maintain a relationship of trust with you. So, when it comes to handling your information, we do so carefully and sensibly, and in ways that live up to that trust. This policy lets you know how we do that, including what information we collect, how we use and protect it, and how you can decide what we do with it. Our goal is to help you understand how we use your information to improve our content, products, advertisements, and services.

what we collect

  * Information you give us
  * Information we collect when you contact us, visit our sites, use our mobile applications or services, use our products or devices, or view our advertisements
  * Information we get from other companies who have obtained your consent to share or sell it or have ensured that other companies from whom they have received your information can share it with them and, in turn, with us and/or other companies
  * Information we get from other companies when you visit their websites

We may combine any and all of this information to help create better products, services, and consumer experiences. 

how we use your information

  * Send you the products and services you ask for
  * Tell you about our and our marketing partners’ products and services
  * Help us run our sites and services

how and when we share your information

  * When we have your consent, with our carefully selected partners so that they can send you offers, promotions, or ads about their products and services we believe you may be interested in
  * With other companies we hire to help us run our business
  * As part of a sale of a P&G brand or business to another company
  * To help us protect our rights or property, e.g., fraud prevention or information security
  * When required by law or government authorities

your choices

You can tell us how we can use your information by clicking on the links below:

  * Marketing communications
  * Interest-based advertising

If you live in the EU, you have certain personal data rights, including to access what personal information we have about you, make corrections or updates to it, tell us to delete that data, or receive a portable copy of that information. These rights don’t apply in all situations. Please click the links below to: 

  * Access or update personal information
  * Request correction, deletion, or transfer of your personal information

We collect information about you in many ways from many places. Some of the information we collect may include personal information that can be used to identify you; for example, your name, email address, telephone number, or postal address. In some countries like those in the EU, things like IP address or cookie and mobile device identifiers may also be considered personal information. 

__Please note__ _: We may combine all of the information we collect about you to give you better products, services, and user experiences._

**you provide it to us.** **** You give us your information when signing up for an account on our websites or in mobile apps or by calling or emailing us. We may ask for things like your name, email or home address, date of birth, payment information, your age, gender, the number of people in your family, and the way you want us to send you information about our products and services—for example, to your home address, email address, or by texting you. 

**from sites and emails.** **** We may use technologies that automatically collect information when you visit our sites, view our advertisements, or use our products or services. For example, we use cookies (a tiny file stored on your computer’s browser) to tell us what browser and operating system you are using, your IP address, web pages you visit, links you click, or whether you have or have not opened an email from us. 

**from mobile applications and internet connected devices.** **** To give you the best possible user experience, we may use technologies that collect information from your phone when you use our mobile apps or from “smart” devices in your home. You consent to do this when downloading the app or installing household internet connected devices. This information could include your mobile phone or other device advertising ID, information about your phone’s operating system, how you use the app or device, and your physical location. You will get a pop up notice on your phone or device that gives you the option to accept or reject allowing us to know your precise geolocation (exactly where you are standing or where you are accessing the internet). 

**from other places.** We may get information that other companies share with or sell to us. For example, you may have given consent for another company to share your personal information with us when you signed up for telecom services or a retailer loyalty points program. We may also collect information from places that you know everyone can see, such as from internet postings, blog entries, videos, or social media sites. We may also receive information from other companies who are in the business of collecting or aggregating information about you sourced from publicly available databases or from consent you have given to their use and subsequently our use of your information. This might be information about your income level, age, gender, number of people in your family, and products you have bought on the internet or from stores in your neighborhood. 

We use your information to help us meet our purpose of touching and improving the lives of people like you every day around the world. We use your information to respond to your questions or requests for information, send you products or samples you have requested, help you manage your P&G site or app preferences, allow you to enter our contests or sweepstakes, or process your payment for the products you buy from us. We may also use your non-personal information (e.g., purchase data, sample requests, etc.) in consumer research or analytics (or personal information when you have consented to participate in such research) to learn more about what consumers want so that we can make new products or improve the ones we already have. 

Another way we use your information is to make sure that what you hear from us is relevant and useful to you as an individual. For example, we may send you information about Gillette® products if you have shown interest in our shaving products by visiting Gillette.com. When we do this, we will use your information – a cookie ID or device ID -- to limit the number of times you see the same advertisement from Gillette. We want you to hear from us about the products you use and love without you hearing the same message over and over again. 

We may also use aggregate information from many people without identifying any individuals to better understand how our websites are being used or to study consumer habits so that we can make products and offer services that meet the needs of all consumers sharing some of the same things in common. For example, we can learn a lot about consumers who are new parents reading our baby product websites, so that we can better serve new parents everywhere with the products and services they want. Use of such non-personal information in this way helps to safeguard your privacy. We will always try to use non-personal information whenever possible for this reason. 

To further protect your privacy, we will also use the least amount of information we can to accomplish the task at hand, put measures in place to prevent mixing information in ways that would allow cookie and device IDs to specifically and directly identify you (e.g., by name), and delete your information when we no longer need it for our business purposes. 

We respect your personal information and take steps to protect it from loss, misuse, or alteration. Where appropriate, these steps can include technical measures like firewalls, intrusion detection and prevention systems, unique and complex passwords, and encryption. We also use organizational and physical measures such as training staff on data processing obligations, identification of data incidents and risks, restricting staff access to your personal information, and ensuring physical security including appropriately securing documents when not being used 

**with other companies.** **** When we have your consent, we may share your information with select partners so they can send you offers, promotions, or ads about products or services we believe you may be interested in. For example, people who receive P&G emails from our diaper brands such as Pampers® may also consent to hear about baby formulas made by other companies. We do not sell your personal information to marketers outside of P&G. We may share information that does not personally identify you with other companies for any purpose.   

**with service providers.** We may need to share your information with companies who help us run our business, including hosting our sites, delivering our emails to you, analyzing the data we collect, and sending you the products and services you requested. We share only the personal information needed for these companies to complete the tasks we request. They are required to protect your information in the same way we do and will not share it or use it for any other purpose. 

**other situations.** If a brand or one of our businesses with which you’ve shared personal data is sold to another company, your data will be shared with that company. As a result, your account and the personal data in it will not be deleted unless you tell the brand or new company that you want it deleted. We may also share your information with companies who help us protect our rights and property, or when required by law or government authorities. 

**marketing** You can tell us to stop sending you email and text messages by following the opt-out instructions sent with these communications. You can also choose to stop receiving marketing email, SMS, or postal mailings by [clicking here](http://www.pg.com/privacy/contact_us/contact_us/privacy-central-contact-interactive.html). While we will honor your choices, we may need to keep information to do so. For example, if you tell us to stop sending marketing emails, we will need your email address on file so that our systems remember that you no longer wish to receive marketing communications to that email address. 

**accounts** Depending upon the country where you registered, your P&G account may offer the ability to access your information and make updates to or delete your data. If not, you can [ click here ](http://www.pg.com/privacy/contact_us/contact_us/privacy-central-contact-interactive.html) to make a request. 

**european union residents.** If you live in the EU, you may access the personal data we hold about you, request that inaccurate, outdated, or no longer necessary information be corrected, erased, or restricted, and ask us to provide your data in a format that allows you to transfer it to another service provider. You also may withdraw your consent at any time where we are relying on your consent for the processing of your personal data. And you may object to our processing of your personal data (this means ask us to stop using it) where that processing is based on our legitimate interest (this means we have a reason for using the data). If you would like more information about data protection and your personal data rights in general, please visit the European Data Protection Supervisor’s site at [ https://edps.europa.eu/data-protection/ ](https://edps.europa.eu/data-protection/) . If you are not happy with our response to your requests, you may lodge a complaint with the data protection authority in your country. Please select from the following options to make your request: 

**_general requests_** . To make a request with respect to personal data used for marketing, which would include for example information you provided us as you registered through one of our websites or apps, please contact us [ here ](https://www.pg.com/privacy/contact_us/contact_us/privacy-central-contact-interactive.html) . 

**_media advertising_** . To make a request with respect to personal data used for advertising, which would include for example information we may have about you at a cookie or device ID level and which we use to provide you with relevant ads, please contact us [here](https://opt-out-png.home.neustar/) . There may also be data associated with your cookie or device ID in our demand-side (or ad-serving) and ad verification partner platforms. For that data, please see [here](http://www.adsrvr.org/) and [here](http://www.mediamath.com/privacy-policy/). 

**_consumer research_** . To make a request with respect to personal data we may have as part of your participation in one of our research studies, please see the contact information provided on your consent form or call or visit your research center. 

**_dental professionals._** If you are a dental professional and have provided your information to us as part of one of our professional outreach programs, including through [https://www.dentalcare.com](https://www.dentalcare.com/), please contact us through the appropriate country numbers and email addresses listed below. 

**Country**

| 

**Call Center**

| 

**E-mail**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Germany 

| 

0203 570 570 

| 

N/A   
  
Austria 

| 

00800 570 570 00 

| 

N/A   
  
Switzerland 

| 

00800 570 570 00 

| 

N/A   
  
UK 

| 

0870 242 1850 

| 

Spain 

| 

900 670 270 

| 

Italy 

| 

+390650972534 

| 

N/A   
  
France 

| 

\+ 33 (0) 825 878 498 

| 

Belgium

| 

For P&G Healthcare:  P&G Health Belgium BVBA, Temselaan 100,  1853 Strombeek-Bever  
  
Netherlands 

| 

N/A 

| 

Poland 

| 

0 801 25 88 25 

| 

N/A   
  
Sweden, Norway, Denmark, Finland 

| 

N/A 

| 

Cookies are small files sent to your computer as you surf the web.  They store useful information about how you interact with the websites you visit.  Cookies do not collect any information stored on your computer or device or in your files.  Cookies do not contain any information that would directly identify you as a person.  Cookies show your computer and device only as randomly assigned numbers and letters (e.g., cookie ID ABC12345) and never as, for example, John E. Smith.     

We use cookies for a number of reasons, such as: 

  * to serve you with relevant advertising 
  * to learn more about the way you interact with P&G content 
  * help us improve your experience when visiting our websites 
  * to remember your preferences, such as a language or a region, so there is no need for you to customize the website on each visit 
  * to identify errors and resolve them 
  * to analyze how well our websites are performing 

These are the types of cookies we use: 

  * **session cookies.** Webpages have no memory. Session cookies remember you (using a randomly generated ID like: ABC12345) as you move from page to page so that you don’t get asked to provide the same information you’ve already given on the site. For example, session cookies are extremely helpful when shopping online—without them the items you place in your shopping cart would disappear by the time you reach the checkout! These cookies are deleted as soon as you leave our site or close your browser. 
  * **persistent cookies.** Persistent cookies allow sites to remember what you prefer when you come back again. For example, if you choose to read the site in French on your first visit, the next time you come back the site will appear automatically in French. Not having to select a language preference every time makes it more convenient, more efficient, and user-friendly for you. 
  * **advertising cookies.** These cookies can be used to learn about what interests you generally might have, based, for example, on the websites you visit and the products you buy. This can also help us infer things about you such your age, marital status, and how many kids you may have. That data allows us to send you ads for products and services that better fit the things you like or need. It also allows us to limit the number of times you see the same advertisement. 
  * **analytics cookies.** These cookies tell us how our websites are working. In many cases, we use Google analytics cookies to monitor the performance of our sites. Our ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to our sites is restricted by the [ Google Analytics Terms of Use ](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) . 

**How you can control cookies.** You can set your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent to your computer. However, this may prevent our sites or services from working properly. You can also set your browser to delete cookies every time you finish browsing. 

**Other Technologies.**

  * **proximity-based beacons.** Beacons send one-way signals to mobile apps you install on your phone over very short distances to tell you, for example, what products are on-sale as you walk through a store. Beacons only talk to your device when you get close enough and after you have given consent within the mobile application associated with a particular beacon. In turn, apps may provide us location information to help customize advertising and offers to you. For example, when you are near a beacon in the skin care section of a supermarket, we may send you a $4 off coupon. ****

  * **pixels.** These are small objects embedded into a web page, but are not visible. They are also known as "tags,” “web bugs,” or "pixel gifs." We use pixels to deliver cookies to your computer, monitor our website activity, make logging into our sites easier, and for online marketing activity. We also include pixels in our promotional email messages or newsletters to determine whether you open and act on them. 

  * **mobile device identifiers and SDKs.** We use software code in our mobile apps to collect information similar to what cookies collect on the internet. This will be information like your mobile phone identifiers (iOS IDFAs and Android Advertising IDs) and the way you use our apps. Similar to cookies, the device information we collect automatically as you use our apps will never identify you as a person. We only know a mobile device as randomly assigned numbers and letters (e.g., advertising ID EFG4567) and never as, for example, John E. Smith. 

  * **precise geolocation.** We may receive information about your exact location from things like global positioning system (GPS) coordinates (longitude and latitude) when you use our mobile apps. You will always get a pop-up notice on your phone or device asking for you to accept or reject allowing us to know exactly where you are in the world. You should understand that we will not always ask for consent to know generally that you are in a broader city, postal code, or province. For example, we do not consider it to be precise location if all we know is that you are somewhere in Manila, Philippines. 

When you visit our partner sites, we can show you ads or other content we believe you would like to see. For example, you may receive advertisements for Tide® laundry detergent if we notice that you are visiting sites that sell children’s clothing or school supplies. And from that information we may conclude that you have children and therefore could well be interested in a powerful laundry-cleaning product. In this way, we intend to send you relevant information about our products that might be of benefit to you. 

**we learn from groups of consumers sharing similar interests.** We may place you into a particular group of consumers who show the same interests. For example, we may put you in the group of “razor aficionados” if we see you frequently purchase razors online or you could be a “bargain-shopper” if we notice you use online coupons or look for discounts or sales. We notice these things about you as you look at web pages, links you click on our websites and other websites you visit, mobile applications you use, or our brand emails you view and links you click in the emails. We group together cookie and device IDs to help us learn about general trends, habits, or characteristics from a group of consumers who all act similarly online and/or offline. By doing this, we can find and serve many others who “look like” those already in the group and thereby send them what we believe will be relevant and beneficial product offers and information. 

**we link other information to your cookie and device IDs.** Your cookie and device IDs may be supplemented with other information, such as information about the products you buy offline or information that you provide directly to us when creating an account on our sites. We generally do this in ways that will not directly personally identify you. For example, we could know that cookie ID ABC12345 belongs to the razor aficionado group based on person’s web site visits, age, gender, and shopping habits, but we would not know that person’s name or address or other information that would identify him or her as a person. Should we ever want to personally identify your cookie or device information (web and app viewing history), we will always ask you before doing so. 

**we may know you across all of your computers, tablets, phones, and devices.** We may know that cookie ID ABC12345 is from a computer that that may be connected to the same person or household owning the mobile phone with device ID EFG15647. This means that you may search for diapers on your laptop, click on a Google search result link which we have sponsored, and then later see an ad for our Pampers® brand diapers on your mobile phone. We might assume or deduce that the same person owns the computer and phone because, for example, they sign on to the same WiFi network every day at the same time. Understanding what devices seem to be used by a person or household helps us limit the number of times you see the same ad across all of your devices. And this is important because that way you don’t get annoyed at us for spamming you with the same ad and we don’t pay for such repetitive ads that we don’t want you to receive. 

**how you can stop receiving interest-based ads.** **** To stop receiving P&G interest-based advertising, you can [ click here ](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/) or click on the WebChoices or AppChoices icons on one of our sites or in one of our mobile applications. **** You can also prevent getting interest-based ads on websites by declining cookies in your browser(s), declining the “access to data” requests that apps usually present when you install them, or by adjusting the ad tracking settings on your device. 

**you will still see “contextual” ads even if you opt out of interest-based ads.** Even if we stop sending you interest-based ads, you will still get ads from our brands on your computer or mobile devices. These ads, however, are based on the context of the sites you visit and are called contextual ads. Unlike interest-based ads which are based on pages you visit on your mobile phone or computer viewing activities, contextual ads are ads shown to you based on the context of the specific site you are visiting. For example, you still may see an ad for one of our baby care brands while looking at nursery products online because these sites traditionally have had mostly new or expecting parents as visitors. You should also know that we may still collect information from your computer or devices and use it for other purposes like evaluating how our websites work, for consumer research, or detecting fraud. 

**deleting cookies also deletes your opt out.** When you opt out of interest-based advertising, we send an opt-out cookie to your browser that tells us that you no longer want to receive interest-based ads from us. Your opt-out cookie will be deleted if you decide to delete _all_ cookies. This means that you will need to opt-out again if you still do not want to receive interest-based ads. 

This section applies only to our processing of personal data of EU country residents. It aims to provide increased transparency into our processing, retention, and transfer of EU resident personal data that is in line with the letter and spirit of the General Data Protection Regulation. 

**entities.** Different P&G entities may be the controller of your personal data. A data controller is the entity which directs the processing activity and is principally responsible for the data. The chart below identifies our data controllers for EU country data. For example, when you register for email on one of our French (.fr) websites, the P&G entity listed next to that country name will be the controller of that personal data (e.g., Procter & Gamble France SAS (LE 577). 

Countries 

| 

Data Controller   
  
---|---  
  
Austria 

| 

Procter & Gamble Austria – Zweigniederlassung der Procter & Gamble GmbH   
  
Bulgaria 

| 

Procter & Gamble Bulgaria EOOD   
  
Romania 

| 

For contests: Procter & Gamble Distribution SRL 

For other sites: Procter & Gamble Marketing Romania SR   
  
Poland 

| 

Procter and Gamble DS Polska sp z o.o.   
  
Belgium

| 

For P&G Healthcare:  P&G Health Belgium BVBA, Temselaan 100,  1853 Strombeek-Bever  
  
Czech Republic 

| 

Procter & Gamble Czech Republic s.r.o.   
  
Hungary 

| 

Procter & Gamble RSC Regionális   
  
Slovakia 

| 

Procter & Gamble, spol. s.r.o.   
  
Croatia 

| 

Procter & Gamble d.o.o. za trgovinu   
  
France 

| 

For P&G HealthCare as of 1 July ‘19 : P&G Health France S.A.S.,   163 Quai Aulagnier, 92600 Asnières-sur-Seine   
  
Germany

| 

For P&G HealthCare: P&G Consumer Health Germany GmbH,  Sulzbacher Strasse 40, 65824 Schwalbach am Taunus  
  
Greece 

| 

P&G Hellas Ltd.   
  
Ireland 

| 

Procter & Gamble UK   
  
Italy 

| 

Procter & Gamble Srl   
  
Netherlands 

| 

Procter & Gamble Nederland B.V.   
  
Portugal 

| 

Procter & Gamble Portugal, Productos de Consumo Higiene de Saude, S.A.   
  
Spain 

| 

Procter & Gamble España, S.A.   
  
EU Countries Not Listed 

| 

Procter & Gamble International Operations SA   
  
United Kingdom

| 

Seven Seas Limited, The Heights, Brooklands, Weybridge, Surrey KT13 0XP  
  
**processing and retention.** As a general rule, we keep your data for only as long as it is needed to complete the purpose for which it was collected or as required by law. We may need to keep your data for longer than our specified retention periods to honor your requests, including to continue keeping you opted out of marketing emails, or to comply with legal or other obligations. This chart tells you the type of data we collect, the purposes for which we use it, why such uses comply with the law (legal basis), and how long we usually keep it (retention period). 

**Type of Data**

| 

**Why We Collect This Data**

| 

**Legal Basis**

| 

**Retention Period**  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
**Marketing**

Email, name, phone number, postal address, your affinities, your interests, your profession, your habits, what you bought, the photos or videos you upload, information about your children and your home, your family composition, the number of people in your household, your hair type, your skin type, your favorite scent, whether you have a pet, etc. 

| 

To send you materials marketing our products or services or the products or services of our partners. 

| 

Your consent for email and SMS and, where we obtain it, consent for postal. Legitimate interests for everything else. 

| 

Until you request to delete the personal data or withdraw your consent. If you do not make such a request, the personal data will be deleted on the following schedule: 

email: after <50 months of all-channel inactivity. We define inactivity through several internal criteria. 

SMS: after <50 months of all-channel inactivity. We define inactivity through several internal criteria. 

postal address: after <50 months of all-channel inactivity. We define inactivity through several internal criteria.   
  
**Contests**

Email, name, phone number, sometimes other data. 

| 

To provide contest participants with information about the contest, including announcing the winner(s) of the contest. 

| 

Your consent. 

| 

For 24 months unless local law requires us to retain it longer.   
  
**Product Purchases**

Email, name, phone number, payment information (including bank account IBAN or Paypal details), sometimes other data. 

| 

To process your purchases of our products, cashback offers, or warranties and to send you relevant communications related to that purchase. 

| 

Your consent. 

| 

As long as necessary to fulfill your order and follow up with communications about your order unless local law requires us to retain it longer. We also generally retain data for 24 months for cashback offers and 10 years for warranties.   
  
**Contact Us**

Email, name, phone number, sometimes other data. 

| 

To address your inquiries and make sure we follow up appropriately or as may be required by law or P&G policy. 

| 

Our legitimate business interest in managing consumer inquiries, as well as your consent for special category data which may be collected in some adverse event cases. 

| 

From 0 to 10 years, depending on the nature of the inquiry, our legitimate interests for processing the data, and our legal obligations.   
  
**Research**

Email, name, phone number, address, identifiable photos or videos, sometimes other data. 

| 

To test our product ideas and learn about your preferences and practices so that we can improve our products and the lives of our consumers. 

| 

Your consent. 

| 

We will retain the personal data collected as part of substantive clinical research for as long as we need it for the purpose for which it was collected, and/or for as long as may be required to retain it by local law or regulation, which may be up to 25 years. For non-clinical research, we will retain your substantive personal data for a maximum of 5 years. We will retain your signed informed consent documents   
  
**Media Targeting**

Advertising cookies, device ID, demographic information such as gender and age, behavioral data such as page views, and sometimes other data. 

| 

To learn about your Internet interests and customize the ads we send you. 

| 

Our legitimate business interests in serving you with relevant advertising. We will obtain your consent for the deployment of cookies on our own websites. 

| 

We will retain this data for thirteen months from the date we collect it or until you opt out, whichever is earlier.   
  
**transfers of your data to other countries.** Your personal information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in a country other than the one in which it was collected, including the United States. For example, we may store your data on a server in the United States because that is where a particular database is hosted; and that data may be “transferred” again when one of our marketers accesses that data from Switzerland to send you a product sample. We perform such transfers, both between P&G entities and between P&G and our service providers, using contractual protections that EU regulators have pre-approved to ensure your data is protected (known as model contract clauses). If you would like a copy of a transfer agreement, [contact us](mailto:euprivacy@pg.com). 

**plugins.** Our websites may include plugins from other companies such as social networks. An example of a plugin is the Facebook “Like” button. These plugins may collect information (e.g., the url of the page you visited) and send it back to the company that created them. This may happen even if you do not click on the plugin. These plugins are governed by the privacy policy and terms of the company that created them, even though they appear on our sites. These plug-ins are non-essential cookies and will only work on our EU sites if you accept cookies. 

**logins.** Our websites may allow you to log in using your account with another company such as, for example, “Login with Facebook.” When you do this, we will have access only to the information that you have given us consent to receive from your account settings in the other company’s account you’re using to log in with. 

**user content.** Some of our sites and apps will allow you to upload your own content for contests, blogs, videos, and other functions. Please remember that any information you submit or post becomes public information. We do not have control over how others may use the content you submit to our sites and apps. We are not responsible for such uses in ways that may violate this privacy policy, the law, or your personal privacy and safety. 

**links.** P&G sites may include links to other sites, which we do not control. Those sites will be governed by their own privacy policies and terms, not ours. 

**children’s online privacy laws.** We follow all applicable data protection laws when collecting personal information online from children. For example, in the EU we do not collect personal information from children under 16 years of age unless we get consent from a parent. Similarly, in the U.S., we obtain verified parental consent when collecting personal information from children younger than 13. 

**california notice for minors.** We may offer interactive services which allow teens under the age of 18 to upload their own content (e.g., videos, comments, status updates, or pictures). This content can be removed or deleted any time by following the instructions on our sites. If you have questions about how to do this, [ contact us](https://www.pg.com/privacy/contact_us/contact_us/privacy-central-contact-interactive.html) Be aware that such posts may have been copied, forwarded, or posted elsewhere by others and we are not responsible for any such actions. You will, in such cases, have to contact other site owners to request removal of your content.
